Self Taught & Motivated

Introduction

My name is **Dyontai Staton**. Born, raised, & reside in **Louisville Kentucky**. I've been in the developmental world for just over **6 years** now. My Career started when I was 12, creating small 2D platform games using C# to play with my brothers. From there I continued down this path into **E-Commerce** and **Web Development** about 3 years ago and started creating & selling numerous eCommerce sites. Starting in April last year I created a team of developers to service **Large & Small Businesses** creating & managing their **Online Presence**. I've done everything from **Designing Sites** through Figma to **Cloud Deployment** of a node server.

Skills

- Experience: FullStack Development for 4+ years & Lead Developer @ StatonFoundation™
 - Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, C#, C++, Python, SQL, PHP, NoSQL
 - Incorporate AGILE / SCRUM Development Process
 - Certified Lead Developer / Programmer With Professional Recognition
 - Managed Numerous High Price Development Contracts
 - Automated Testing With Debugging & Analysis
 - Ability To Teach Development Concepts
 - User Requirement Gathering
 - All Skills were Self-taught & Gained From Working With Professional Clients

Education

- ACT Score: 32
- GPA: 3.2

Southern High School, Louisville

Computer Science & Cyber Science Career Pathway | August 2016 - May 2020

- Coding Club August 2019 May 2020
- Beta Club August 2018 May 2020
- Advance Placement August 2016-2020

University Of Louisville

Bachelors of Science of Software Development, 2021-2023

Self Taught & Motivated

Professional Experience

Freelancing Contracts

April 2016 - Current

NowUs.com - Los Angeles California (Dec 2019 - Current)

Full Stack Development of Video Streaming Platform - Start to Finish

(Figma + React + Javascript + Node + Redux + Google Cloud + Docker + Sass + GraphQL)

- Manage & Lead Development, Performing Varying Tasks on Contract Basis
- Design Site Front-end Completely Within Figma
- Create & Meet Deadlines For Both Myself + Team
- Communications With Client Company to Determine Client Needs & Design Goals
- Application Optimization Based On A/B Testing
- Documentation & Change-log to keep team up-to-date on changes
- Integrated Open-Source into the project's code base while staying secure.
- Containerized Project to allow for Cloud Deployment
- Team Worked Both Remote & At Office
- Secure PayPal Subscription Payment Integration
- User Account Feature
- Video Streaming Feature With Stream Control
- Possibility Of App Development
- Collaboration with Million Dollar Company
- Automated Email Sender Through Database Triggers
- Facebook Pixel & Google Analytics Integration
- Admin Dashboard with site's videos & user controls.

Client Testimony

"This guy was AMAZING... I would hire him AGAIN and AGAIN. based in the USA... great communicator... perfect written english - I used him to create code for a very unique specific type of website and he hit a home run!!! 100% SATISFIED!!! "

Self Taught & Motivated

Personal Projects

StatonFoundation[™]

Web & Application Development Freelancing Team of 3 | 2019 - Current

- Managed & Lead Team of Developers
- 56 Finished Contracts With 94% Finished On Time
- Maintained 5 Star Ratings on Freelancer Sites

Client Testimony

"Extremely professional, quick and knowledgeable!"

Staton.cc

Official Site of StatonFoundation™

- Made With React & Firebase
- Database Integration
- FullStack Development
- Optimized SEO Integration
- Bundled With Webpack

Dyontai.com

My Personal Portfolio

- Made With React & Hosted Through Firebase
- User Account Feature | Connection To Database
- It's Simply Just Cool

WebBase

In-house Web Development **Boilerplate** @ StatonFoundation™

- Base React Component Presets
- Global Styling Theme System Using Styled-Components
- Easy Firebase Integration For Graceful Hosting
- Clean Coding Architecture
- Maintained On Github to be Used as a Template for Later Projects

Self Taught & Motivated

APIBase

In-house GraphQL API Server Boilerplate @ StatonFoundation™

- GraphQL Clean Code Architecture
- Uses Express Framework to Serve Data
- Node.js Environment
- Pre-Dockerization For Quick Cloud Deployment
- Modular Code-base

AppBase

In-house Mobile Application Boilerplate @ StatonFoundation™

- Base React Component Presets
- Using React Native
- Easy Firebase Integration For Graceful Hosting
- Clean Coding Architecture
- Maintained On Github to be Used as a Template for Later Projects

DesktopBase

In-house Desktop Application Boilerplate @ StatonFoundation™

- Base React Component Presets
- Using React & Electron
- Easy Firebase Integration For Graceful Hosting
- Clean Coding Architecture
- Maintained On Github to be Used as a Template for Later Projects

Manikin

Discord Music Streaming ChatBot

- 20+ Music Commands
- Stream Audio Data From YouTube
- Auto-Play Feature
- YouTube Playlist Info Web Scraper
- Video Search Feature Using YouTube API
- Hosted Within Docker Container Run On Raspberry Pi Kubernetes Cluster

Realms®

Discord Mini-Game ChatBot

- Group System | Integrates With Discord Roles
- Profile System | Connection To Database
- Claim System | Allows Users To Raid Other Users Claims
- Item System | Crafting & Resources
- Vender System | User Economy Store Features